<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>$200 Salad Dressing</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Dressing</cat>
        <cat>Salad</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Contributed by Mrs. C. C.</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Robbins, Chicago</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Posted by Perry Lowell,</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>COOKING Echo, Jan. '92</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>Text:</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Mr. and Mrs. Robbins were taking a motor trip last year through</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  the South.  At one of the Southern hotels they were served a salad dressing
  which more than delighted their tastes.  Asking if they might have the
  recipe, they were told to leave their name and their address and it would
  be mailed to them. On their return, they found the recipe with a bill for
  $200.00.  Aghast, they consulted their lawyer and were told that inasmuch
  as they had ordered with- out asking the price, they would have to pay.
  Feeling that so costly a recipe should be shared with many, Mrs. Robbins
  had copies made and sent to her friends. Try it and we think you'll smack
  your lips.
  
  2 teaspoons salt 2 teaspoons dry mustard 2 teaspoons paprika 2 teaspoons
  celery seed or ground celery seed 3/4 cup sugar 1/2 cup vinegar 2 cups
  Mazola oil 2 tablespoons grated onions
  
  Put together in the top of a double boiler and stir well. Then place the
  boiler in a bowl of quite warm water. Stirring and feeling with the finger
  to see that it gets to less than blood warmth just off the cold. Then
  remove double boiler and beat with a rotary egg beater until thick. Put
  into a bottle.  Keep in refrigerator and shake well before using. Do not
  let mixture get too warm. It will not thicken if you do. Submitted to the
  cookbook by:  Miriam Eaton
  
  From: Perry Lowell Info: Westminster Presbyterian Church Cookbook, circa
  1950
  
                                        Date:
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
