<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>( From Bread Mix ) Big Soft Pretzels</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Breadmaker</cat>
        <cat>Mixes</cat>
        <cat>Kids!</cat>
        <cat>Breads</cat>
        <cat>Snacks</cat></categories>
      <yield>1</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Dry yeast</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>5</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Bread mix; up to six lukewarm water</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Eggs; beaten</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>TOPPING</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg; beaten</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2</qty>
            <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
          <item>Coarse salt</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter; melted</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Lightly grease 2 large baking sheets.  In a large bowl, dissolve yeast in
  lukewarm water.  Blend in 2 eggs and butter. Add 5 cups bread mix. Stir
  well.  Add additional bread mix to make a soft, but not too sticky dough.
  Knead about 5 minutes until dough is smooth. Roll pieces of dough into
  ropes about 1/2 inch in diameter and 18 to 24 inches long. Form into
  pretzel shapes.  For pretzel sticks, cut dough into 5 to 6 inch lengths.
  Place on prepared baking sheets. Preheat oven to 425.
  
  Brush tops of pretzels with beaten egg and sprinkle with coarse salt. Bake
  immediately 12 to 15 minutes, until brown and crisp. Makes 12 to 15 large
  pretzels.
  
  Variation For a chewier pretzel, drop pretzel-shaped dough into a pan of
  boiling water.  When dough floats to the top of the water, remove it.
  Preheat oven to 400. Brush with egg and sprinkle with coarse salt. Bake
  about 30 minutes.
  
  All of these recipes I have posted using my bread mix can be adjusted to
  use with the bread machine, some using the dough setting. I have had
  excellent results. Will try to post more over the weekend as I get time.
  Also have a lot of other "mix" recipes if anyone is interested.
  
  Formatted by Elaine Radis BGMB90B; JUNE, 1993
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
