<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>(Injera) Ethiopian Flat Bread</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>None</cat></categories>
      <yield>15 -20</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Self-rising flour; (750 ml)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Whole wheat flour; (125 ml)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Teff flour; (from African grocery or health food store)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Cornmeal or masa harina; (125 ml)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Active dry yeast; (one package) (15 ml)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Warm water; (875 ml)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  15-20 12-inch Injera
  
  In a large bowl, mix:
  
  Let set in large bowl, covered, an hour or longer, until batter rises and
  becomes stretchy. It can sit as long as 3-6 hours.
  
  When ready, stir batter if liquid has settled on bottom. Whip in blender, 2
  cups of batter at a time, thinning it with 1/2 - 3/4 cup water. Batter will
  be quite thin.
  
  Cook in non-stick frypan WITHOUT OIL over medium or medium-high heat. Use
  1/2 cup batter per injera for a 12-inch pan or 1/3 cup batter for a 10-inch
  pan. Pour batter in heated pan and quickly swirl pan to spread batter as
  thin as possible.
  
  Batter should be no thicker than 1/8-inch. Do not turn over. Injera does
  not easily stick or burn. It is cooked through when bubbles appear all over
  the top.
  
  Finished injera will be thicker than a crepe, but thinner than a pancake.
  
  Lay each injera on a clean towel for a minute or two, then stack in covered
  dish to keep warm.
  
  To serve, overlap a few injera on a platter and place stews on top ( most
  kinds of spicy bean or veggie stews/curries would be great with this. For
  Ethiopian food, the spicier the better).
  
  Or lay one injera on each dinner plate, and ladle stew servings on top.
  Give each person three or more injera, rolled up or folded in quarters, to
  use for scooping up the stews.
  
  If you make 15 12-inch injeras, each would be about 120 calories, 3% CFF.
  
  Posted to fatfree digest V97 #287 by Sandy Laken &lt;globlcit@erols.com&gt; on
  Dec 06, 1997
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
