<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>(Reduced-Sugar) Peach-Pineapple Spread</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Canning</cat>
        <cat>Fruits</cat></categories>
      <yield>5</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Drained peach pulp (procedure as below)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Drained crushed pineapple (unsweetened)</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Bottled lemon juice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Sugar (optional)</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  This recipe may be made with any combination of peaches, nectarines,
  apricots, and plums.
  
  This recipe may be made without sugar or with up to 2 cups, according to
  taste or preference. Non-nutritive sweeteners may be added. If aspartame (a
  low-calorie nutritive sweetener) is used, the sweetening power of aspartame
  may be lost within 3 to 4 weeks.
  
  Yield: 5 to 6 half-pints
  
  Procedure: Thoroughly wash 4 to 6 pounds of firm, ripe peaches. Drain well.
  Peel and remove pits. Grind fruit flesh with a medium or coarse blade, or
  crush with a fork (do not use a blender). Place ground or crushed fruit in
  a 2-quart saucepan. Heat slowly to release juice, stirring constantly,
  until fruit is tender. Place cooked fruit in a jelly bag or strainer lined
  with four layers of cheesecloth. Allow juice to drip about 15 minutes. Save
  the juice for jelly or other uses. Measure 4 cups of drained fruit pulp for
  making spread. Combine the 4 cups of pulp, pineapple, and lemon juice in a
  4-quart saucepan. Add up to 2 cups of sugar, if desired, and mix well. Heat
  and boil gently for 10 to 15 minutes, stirring enough to prevent sticking.
  Fill jars quickly, leaving 1/4-inch headspace.
  
  Adjust lids and process as recommended in Table 1.
  
  Table 1. Recommended process time for Peach-Pineapple Spread in a
  boiling-water canner.
  
  Style of Pack: Hot.  Jar Size: Half-pints. Process Time at Altitudes of 0 -
  1,000 ft: 15 min
                         1,001 - 3,000 ft: 20 min.
                         3,001 - 6,000 ft: 20 min.
                           Above 6,000 ft: 25 min.
  
  Style of Pack: Hot.  Jar Size: Pints. Process Time at Altitudes of 0 -
  1,000 ft: 20 min
                         1,001 - 3,000 ft: 25 min.
                         3,001 - 6,000 ft: 30 min.
                           Above 6,000 ft: 35 min.
  
  ======================================================= === * USDA
  Agriculture Information Bulletin No. 539 (rev. 1994) * Meal-Master format
  courtesy of Karen Mintzias
  
  From Gemini's MASSIVE MealMaster collection at www.synapse.com/~gemini
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
