<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>1-2-3 Meurbeteig Dough (Mellow Dough)</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Bread</cat></categories>
      <yield>12</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing-div>
        <title/>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1/2</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Sugar</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>cup</unit></amt>
          <item>Butter</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>2 3/4</qty>
            <unit>cups</unit></amt>
          <item>Flour</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Egg yolk</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Vanilla</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Cold water; wine or brandy</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Grated lemon rind</item></ing></ing-div>
      <ing-div>
        <title>OPTIONAL</title>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty>1</qty>
            <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
          <item>Baking powder for kuchens</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Cocoa or melted choclate</item></ing>
        <ing>
          <amt>
            <qty/>
            <unit/></amt>
          <item>Ground almonds</item></ing></ing-div></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  Date: Fri, 23 Feb 96 7:49:28 EST
  
  submitted by: LIR119@delphi.com
  
  The all purpose European pastry dough!  Translated Meurbeteig means "mellow
  dough." The basic method for this versile dough which can be made into many
  variations starts with the principle of: one part weight sugar, double
  weight butter and triple weight flour. The cup amounts above are
  approximates. Just weigh ingredeints for the most accurate measurements.
  Combine the flour, butter and sugar and stir in enough egg yolk with
  vanilla, wine, and lemon to taste to bind the dough. The dough can be made
  batter like, softer or firmer as desired. this is the outstanding feature
  of this dough to change it to your liking. For kuchens the dough can be
  made into a texture to spread or pat into the pan, although normally no
  baking powder is used, a teaspoon made be added for kuchen type doughs.
  Normally the dough is like a short dough similar to tart pastry.Basically
  for softer doughs, increase the egg yolks and decrease the flour. for
  chocolate variations add some baking cocoa or melted choclate. For a tangy
  dough add some sour cream, or grated cheese for a cheese pastry dough.
  blend in almonds for a nut dough. Of importance is that the dough should be
  prepared quickly  and chilled prior to using if used for tart shells or
  pastries. Then it can be rolled out to fit tart pans etc. Prick the dough
  with tines of a fork when used for tart pastires. For kuchens the dough
  need not be chilled and may be used immediately. Double recipe if
  desired.Follow individual recipes, baking temperature usually from 350 to
  375. Dough freezes well.
  
  DAVE &lt;DAVIDG@CLAM.RUTGERS.EDU&gt;
  
  RECIPEINTERNET LIST SERVER
  
  From the 'RECIPEinternet: Recipes from Around the World' recipe list.
  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe Archive, http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
