<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>1-Pot Vegetable Bean Casserole</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Vegetables</cat>
        <cat>Pastanoodle</cat>
        <cat>Casseroles</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garlic cloves, minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Onions, chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Carrots, diced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>tablespoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Red wine vinegar</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Dried rosemary, crushed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pinch</unit></amt>
        <item>Hot pepper flakes</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Spaghetti sauce</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>19</qty>
          <unit>ounces</unit></amt>
        <item>Can Romano or kidney beans, drained and rinsed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Rotini pasta</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Broccoli, chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/3</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Romano cheese, fresh grated</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  In nonstick skillet, melt butter over medium-low heat; cook garlic, onions
  and carrots, covered, for about 10 minutes or until softened. Stir in
  vinegar, rosemary, pepper and hot pepper flakes; cook, covered, for about
  15 minutes or until onions are very soft. Stir in sauce; bring to boil.
  Reduce heat; simmer for about 5 minutes or until thickened. Stir in beans;
  set aside.
  
  Meanwhile, in large pot of boiling salted water, cook pasta for 5 minutes.
  Add broccoli; [tip: peel broccoli stalks so that they will cook in the same
  amount of time as the florets.] cook for about 1 minute or until pasta is
  almost tender and broccoli is bright green and still crisp. Drain and
  return to pot. Stir in tomato mixture. Pour into greased 8-inch square
  baking dish; sprinkle with Romano cheese. Cover with foil.
  
  [Can be prepared to this point and cooled in refrigerator. Cove and
  refrigerate for up to 4 hours. Let stand at room temperature for 30 minutes
  before baking. Add 30 minutes to baking time.]
  
  Bake in 350F 180C oven for about 35 minutes or until heated through. Broil,
  uncovered, for about 2 minutes or until browned and bubbly.
  
  Serve with crisp cucumber and red onion salad.
  
  4 servings for $10.14CDN [Nov 95]
  
  Per Serving: about 540 calories, 21 g protein, 15 g fat, 85 g carbohydrate,
  very high source fibre, good source calcium, excellent source iron
  
  Source: Canadian Living magazine, Nov 95 Presented in article "Hearty &amp;
  Healthy: Casseroles See The Light" Recipe by Canadian Living Test Kitchen
  
      [-=PAM=-]   PA_Meadows@msn.com
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest V3 #342
  
  From: "Paul A Meadows" &lt;PA_Meadows@msn.com&gt;
  
  Date: Sat, 14 Dec 96 21:52:40 UT
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
