<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>1-Pot Shrimp Casserole</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Fish*shell</cat>
        <cat>Casseroles</cat></categories>
      <yield>4</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Long-grain rice</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Egg white</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh parsley, chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Butter</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Garlic clove, minced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh mushrooms, sliced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>cup</unit></amt>
        <item>Celery, sliced</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Green onion, chopped</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Dried dillweed</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Raw unpeeled shrimp</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>All-purpose flour</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1 1/2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Milk</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>GruyŠre, shredded</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Lemon rind, grated</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Fresh bread crumbs</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>  This can be made with any combination of seafood, such as scallops, crab or
  lobster. Serve with green beans and endive salad.
  
  In saucepan, bring 1-1/2 cups salted water to boil. Stir in rice; cover and
  simmer over low heat for 15-20 minutes or until tender and water is
  absorbed. Remove from heat; stir in egg white and 1 tb of the parsley.
  Press mixture into bottom of greased 8-inch square baking dish or other
  shallow heat proof casserole with same volume; set aside.
  
  Meanwhile, in nonstick skillet, melt 1 tb of the butter over medium-high
  heat; cook garlic, mushrooms and celery, stirring, for about 5 minutes or
  just until vegetables start to brown. Stir in onions, dill and 1/4 ts each
  of the salt and pepper; cook over high heat for about 2 minutes or until
  lightly browned. transfer to large bowl.
  
  Whip out skillet; pour in 2 cups water and bring to simmer. Cook shrimp for
  about 1 minute or just until pink. Reserve 1 cup of liquid, rinse shrimp
  under cold running water. Shell and devein shrimp; arrange over rice in
  baking dish.
  
  In heavy saucepan, melt remaining butter over medium heat; stir in flour.
  Cook, stirring, for about 2 minutes, without browning; gradually whisk in
  reserved liquid and milk. Cook, stirring, for about 20 minutes or until
  thickened. Remove from heat; stir in 1/2 cup of the cheese, lemon rind and
  remaining salt and pepper until cheese is melted. Stir into vegetable
  mixture along with remaining parsley; pour over shrimp in baking dish.
  
  [Can be prepared to this point, covered and refrigerated for up to 1 day.
  Let stand at room temperature for 30 minutes before baking.]
  
  In small bowl, stir together remaining cheese and bread crumbs. Sprinkle
  evenly over casserole. Bake in 325F 160C oven for 40-50 minutes or until
  heated through. Broil for about 2 minutes or until top is golden. Let stand
  for 15 minutes.
  
  4 servings for $17.01CDN [Nov 95]
  
  Per Serving: about 480 calories, 32 g protein, 19 g fat, 43 g carbohydrate,
  excellent source calcium, good source iron
  
  Tip: For added colour, substitute 1/4 cup wild rice for long-grain rice.
  cook wild rice for 30 minutes before adding long-grain rice. Source:
  Canadian Living magazine, Nov 95 Presented in article "Hearty &amp; Healthy:
  Casseroles See The Light" Recipe by Canadian Living Test Kitchen
  
      [-=PAM=-]   PA_Meadows@msn.com
  Posted to MM-Recipes Digest V3 #342
  
  From: "Paul A Meadows" &lt;PA_Meadows@msn.com&gt;
  
  Date: Sat, 14 Dec 96 21:52:40 UT
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
