<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<recipeml version="0.5">
  <recipe>
    <head>
      <title>10-75 Chili</title>
      <categories>
        <cat>Meat</cat></categories>
      <yield>10</yield></head>
    <ingredients>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>pounds</unit></amt>
        <item>Ground round</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>pound</unit></amt>
        <item>Bulk Italian sausage</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>4</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>"Basic Brown Soup Stock" or canned beef broth</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Saffron threads</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>3</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Olive oil</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>cups</unit></amt>
        <item>Shallots; chopped coarse</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Garlic; chopped fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>(10-oz) green chiles; chopped fine</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Oregano</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Whole cumin seeds</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1/2</qty>
          <unit>teaspoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Cayenne pepper</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>2</qty>
          <unit>tablespoons</unit></amt>
        <item>Chili powder</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>teaspoon</unit></amt>
        <item>Salt</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty/>
          <unit/></amt>
        <item>Fresh ground black pepper to taste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>(6-oz) tomato paste</item></ing>
      <ing>
        <amt>
          <qty>1</qty>
          <unit>can</unit></amt>
        <item>(30-oz) red kidney beans drained</item></ing></ingredients>
    <directions>
      <step>    We recently invited firehouse cooks to send in their favorite recipes. We
  ran a contest and the results can be seen in this recipe and the "19-Alarm
  Chili" recipe.  The most frequently submitted dish was chili. That makes
  great sense since firehouse cooks often have to stop cooking right in the
  middle of the preparation of the dish and then come back to it later. The
  dish needs to stand up to this kind of treatment. Chili can take it. We
  have chosen two of the most interesting chili dishes and offer them to you
  without any explanation. While chili didn't win the contest, we certainly
  did gain some insight into the meaning of chili. SERVES 10-12
  
    Robert Vazquez, of Engine Company 212 in Brooklyn, New York, sent in a
  recipe that caught the eyes of all of us. He offered strange additions that
  made me think this man is a serious cook; additions such as saffron and
  shallots. You would not think that these subtle and expensive ingredients
  would come through, but they do. This is a delicious dish !
  
    I should also tell you that Bob's motto is "You light 'em, we fight 'em!"
  He is referring to chili?
  
    In a large, heavy skillet, brown ground meat and sausage. Transfer to a
  4-quart pot. In the same skillet add beef stock and bring to a boil. Remove
  stock from heat. Crumble saffron and add to the stock. Set this aside in a
  separate bowl. Add olive oil to the skillet and cook the shallots and
  garlic for 5 minutes, stirring frequently. Remove from heat. Add canned
  chiles, oregano, cumin seeds, cayenne pepper, chili powder, salt, and a few
  grindings of black pepper. Stir together, then add tomato paste and beef
  stock. Mix together thoroughly. Add this to the meat and bring to a boil.
  Stir. Reduce heat and simmer in half-covered pot for 1-1/2 hours. Add beans
       10    minutes before completion.
  
  From &lt;The Frugal Gourmet Cooks American&gt;.  Downloaded from Glen's MM Recipe
  Archive, http://www.erols.com/hosey.
 
</step></directions></recipe></recipeml>
